[
    {
        "id": 0,
        "question": "How long have snakes been roaming the Earth for?",
        "options": {
            "a": "3 million years",
            "b": "30 million years",
            "c": "130 million years",
            "d": "200 million years"
        },
        "answerkey": "c"
    },
    {
        "id": 1,
        "question": "What characteristics do all snakes share?",
        "options": {
            "a": "They are carnivoes",
            "b": "They are all programming languages",
            "c": "They're all cold-blooded",
            "d": "They are both carnivores and cold-blooded"
        },
        "answerkey": "c"
    },
    {
        "id": 2,
        "question": "How do snakes hear?",
        "options": {
            "a": "With small ears",
            "b": "Through their skin",
            "c": "Through their tail",
            "d": "They don't use their ears at all"
        },
        "answerkey": "b"
    },
    {
        "id": 3,
        "question": "What can't snakes see?",
        "options": {
            "a": "Colour",
            "b": "Light",
            "c": "Both of the above",
            "d": "Other snakes"
        },
        "answerkey": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 4,
        "question": "What unique vision ability do boas and pythons possess?",
        "options": {
            "a": "Night vision",
            "b": "Infrared vision",
            "c": "See through walls",
            "d": "They don't have vision"
        },
        "answerkey": "b"
    },
    {
        "id": 5,
        "question": "How does a snake smell?",
        "options": {
            "a": "Quite pleasant",
            "b": "Through its nose",
            "c": "Through its tongues",
            "d": "Both through its nose and its tongues"
        },
        "answerkey": "d"
    },
    {
        "id": 6,
        "question": "Where are Jacobson's organs located in snakes?",
        "options": {
            "a": "Mouth",
            "b": "Tail",
            "c": "Stomach",
            "d": "Liver"
        },
        "answerkey": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 7,
        "question": "Snakes have very similar internal organs compared to humans. Snakes, however; lack the following:",
        "options": {
            "a": "A diaphragm",
            "b": "Intestines",
            "c": "Lungs",
            "d": "Kidney"
        },
        "answerkey": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 8,
        "question": "Snakes have different shaped lungs than humans. What do snakes have?",
        "options": {
            "a": "An elongated right lung",
            "b": "A small left lung",
            "c": "Both of the above",
            "d": "None of the above"
        },
        "answerkey": "c"
    },
    {
        "id": 9,
        "question": "What's true about two-headed snakes?",
        "options": {
            "a": "They're a myth!",
            "b": "They rarely survive in the wild",
            "c": "They're very dangerous",
            "d": "They can kiss each other"
        },
        "answerkey": "b"
    },
    {
        "id": 10,
        "question": "What substance covers a snake's skin?",
        "options": {
            "a": "Calcium",
            "b": "Keratin",
            "c": "Copper",
            "d": "Iron"
        },
        "answerkey": "b"
    },
    {
        "id": 11,
        "question": "What snake doesn't have to have a mate to lay eggs?",
        "options": {
            "a": "Copperhead",
            "b": "Cornsnake",
            "c": "Kingsnake",
            "d": "Flower pot snake"
        },
        "answerkey": "d"
    },
    {
        "id": 12,
        "question": "What snake is the longest?",
        "options": {
            "a": "Green anaconda",
            "b": "Reticulated python",
            "c": "King cobra",
            "d": "Kingsnake"
        },
        "answerkey": "b"
    },
    {
        "id": 13,
        "question": "Though invasive species can now be found in the Everglades, in which three continents are pythons (members of the family Pythonidae) found in the wild?",
        "options": {
            "a": "Africa, Asia and Australia",
            "b": "Africa, Australia and Europe",
            "c": "Africa, Australia and South America",
            "d": "Africa, Asia and South America"
        },
        "answerkey": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 14,
        "question": "Pythons are held as some of the most dangerous snakes on earth, but are often confused with anacondas. Which of these is *not* a difference between pythons and anacondas?",
        "options": {
            "a": "Pythons suffocate their prey, anacondas crush them",
            "b": "Pythons lay eggs, anacondas give birth to live young",
            "c": "Pythons grow longer, anacondas grow heavier",
            "d": "Pythons generally spend less time in water than anacondas do"
        },
        "answerkey": "a"
    },
    {
        "id": 15,
        "question": "Pythons are unable to chew their food, and so swallow prey whole. Which of these methods is most commonly demonstrated to help a python to swallow large prey?",
        "options": {
            "a": "The python's stomach pressure is reduced, so prey is sucked in",
            "b": "An extra set of upper teeth 'walk' along the prey",
            "c": "The python holds its head up, so prey falls into its stomach",
            "d": "Prey is pushed against a barrier and is forced down the python's throat"
        },
        "answerkey": "b"
    },
    {
        "id": 16,
        "question": "Pythons, like many large constrictors, possess vestigial hind limbs. Whilst these 'spurs' serve no purpose in locomotion, how are they put to use by some male pythons? ",
        "options": {
            "a": "To store sperm",
            "b": "To release pheromones",
            "c": "To grip females during mating",
            "d": "To fight off rival males"
        },
        "answerkey": "c"
    },
    {
        "id": 17,
        "question": "Pythons tend to travel by the rectilinear method (in straight lines) when on land, as opposed to the concertina method (s-shaped movement). Why do large pythons tend not to use the concertina method? ",
        "options": {
            "a": "Their spine is too inflexible",
            "b": "They move too slowly",
            "c": "The scales on their backs are too rigid",
            "d": "They are too heavy"
        },
        "answerkey": "d"
    }
]
